# Luke Vella

# Developer & UI/UX Designer

#### Website

lukevella.com

#### Email

me@lukevella.com

#### **Skills**

#### **Frontend**

Javascript (ES2015), HTML, CSS, webpack, ReactJS (Redux), Jest

#### **Backend**

NodeJS, MongoDB, Docker

#### iOS

Swift, Objective-C

#### Other

Git, AWS, Heroku, Unix

# **Side Projects**

# react-activity

Open source library of activity indicators for react applications.

#### Rallly

Open source collaborative scheduling application.

#### **Freeshot**

Dribbble client for iOS.

#### Social

# Linkedin

@lukevella

# Github

@lukevella

#### **Dribbble**

@lukevella

# **Summary**

I am a multidisciplinary developer with over 8 years of professional experience. I've delivered multiple products to market, often overseeing projects from concept, through design and completion. My strong design background allows me to both communicate my thoughts effectively when working in a team but also work independently.

## **Experience**

SAP SE Berlin

Full-stack Developer

- Worked with a talented team of machine learning experts and developers to build a scalable invoice data extraction service
- Created a service-oriented architecture and introduced Docker to facilitate development and deployment of micro-services

# **NOA Technologies (formerly LOCK8)**

Berlin

Front-end Developer, UI/UX Designer

Jun 2015 - Feb 2016

Mar 2016 - Mar 2017

- Led the design & development of a web based fleet management system
- Set up workflows for development and deployment of the product across multiple environments

Float.travel Remote

Full-stack Developer, iOS Developer

Sep 2014 - May 2015

- Built a native iOS application that offered free and paid walking tours
- Developed a RESTful API that served content from a CMS to the mobile application
- Modularized the application to allow the production of a white label solution

Zeepex Malta

Front-end Developer, UI/UX Designer

Jul 2012 - Dec 2014

- Built a single-page application that offered advanced search, data management and other tools that aimed to facilitate sourcing for recruiters
- Developed an isomorphic javascript application that could intelligently discover social media profiles belonging to an individual

AWHPoker Malta

Front-end Developer, UI/UX Designer

Feb 2009 - Dec 2011

- Built a web application that allowed users to view information from the gaming network's back-office
- Designed and developed multiple web sites based on Wordpress

## **Education**

# **University of Malta**

B.Sc. (Hons.) Computer Science & Artificial Intelligence